eloan.com 2016-09-18

# E-LOAN’s Privacy Policy

Last revision date: June 27, 2016

This privacy policy describes how E-LOAN, Inc. (“E-LOAN”, “We”, “Our” or “Us”), a wholly owned subsidiary of Banco Popular North America (“BPNA”), collects and uses the personal information you provide on E-LOAN’s Web site: www.eloan.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding E-LOAN’s use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. Products and services are intended for U.S. Residents over 18 years of age.

Please be aware that other Web sites that you may access through the E-LOAN Web site may collect personal information about you. E-LOAN’s Privacy Policy does not cover those third party Web sites, and E-LOAN encourages you to read those third party privacy policies prior to providing them with your personal information. To assist you with reading through E-LOAN’s Privacy Policy, E-LOAN has provided answers to questions you may find most important, and have created the following sections:

  * How does E-LOAN collect and use my information?
  * Does E-LOAN share my personal information with third parties?
  * What information is shared on savings and CD products?
  * Can I opt-out of communications from E-LOAN?
  * How does E-LOAN safeguard my personal information?
  * Will this Privacy Policy change?
  * What is E-Loan’s Deposit Privacy Policy?

**HOW DOES E-LOAN COLLECT AND USE MY INFORMATION?**

E-LOAN may collect and use your personal information to respond to your requests for financial products and services offered on E-LOAN’s Web site or to provide you with information about products or services that may be of value to you. Certain personal information E-LOAN collects about you may be publicly available via government records, telephone books, and other widely available media (i.e. the Internet). However, we treat all information you provide to E-LOAN as non-public.

1\. Information you provide

E-LOAN collects the personal information you provide when you:

  * Contact E-LOAN with a question or suggestion
  * Open a Savings Account or Certificate of Deposit

E-LOAN collects certain information from you when you open a savings account or certificate of deposit vis-à-vis the E-LOAN Web site. This includes personal information such as name, email address, address, social security number, and bank account and routing numbers. This allows you to transfer money between accounts and lets E-LOAN facilitate the transactions.Contacting E-LOAN

When you contact E-LOAN with a question or suggestion we collect your name, email address, and telephone number. E-LOAN only uses personal information that it collects to respond to and/or resolve your question or concern.

2\. Information collected from other sources

E-LOAN may also collect information about you from the following sources:

  * Consumer reporting agency: E-LOAN uses this information to process your account.

3\. Technical Information

We use technology to:

  * Gather technical information from your Web browser (IP address, operating systems);
  * Set persistent cookies on your computer; which are not linked to personal information and
  * Collect anonymous, non-personal information about your navigation throughout our website by using “cookies”, “action tags”, invisible “gifs” placed on the E-LOAN Web site by E-LOAN or its business partners.

E-LOAN uses this information for routine Web site maintenance; to establish that you are a unique user and/or for purposes of assessing the effectiveness of the E-LOAN Web site and the products and services offered.

4\. Third Party Advertisements

E-LOAN uses third party advertising companies to provide advertisements on the E-LOAN website.

**DOES E-LOAN SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES?**

E-LOAN may share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

  * With affiliate companies (companies related by common ownership or control).

Examples: E-LOAN may share information about your transactions, experiences or your creditworthiness with its affiliates, BPNA, Popular Equipment Finance, Inc., and Popular Insurance Agency USA, Inc. Access BPNA’s Privacy Policy here and BPNA’s Privacy Practices here.

  * With companies involved in the loan or savings account process.

Examples: Credit reporting agencies are a necessary part of various banking transactions. Therefore, E-LOAN must provide some of your information to these companies in order to process your account.

  * With companies that perform services on our behalf (Joint marketing).

Examples: E-LOAN sometimes uses service providers to assist it with specific processes or functions such as distributing emails or collecting survey information from E-LOAN customers. E-LOAN requires the service providers it uses to sign business agreements that restrict their use of your information to fulfilling the contracted service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us and for no other purposes.

  * As required by law.

Examples: E-LOAN may need to share your information with law enforcement or government agencies in response to a subpoena, state/federal audit or other similar circumstances. If E-LOAN is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on the E-LOAN Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. The E-LOAN Web site may link you to other companies’ Web sites that offer services that may be of interest to you. These companies do not obtain any specific information about you or your transaction on the E-LOAN Web site. You may also access the E-LOAN Web site from another company’s Web site. E-LOAN may collect Web traffic statistics from you and other consumers’ Web browsers, and we may share this aggregated information with outside companies to assist them with assessing the effectiveness of their Web site content. No personal information is shared in this aggregated information.

**WHAT INFORMATION IS SHARED ON SAVINGS AND CD PRODUCTS?**

When you open a savings account or certificate of deposit through E-LOAN, an account is created for you with our parent company, Banco Popular North America (BPNA), a FDIC-member institution and a New York state chartered bank. These deposit accounts are FDIC insured through BPNA. BPNA will use your information solely to provide services on these accounts.

**CAN I OPT-OUT OF COMMUNICATIONS FROM E-LOAN?**

E-LOAN always provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of electronic communications that offer our products and services. You can opt-out of marketing communications at anytime by clicking on the following link: https://savings.eloan.com/optout and completing the applicable section(s). However, please be aware that E-LOAN also sends service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do not have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

**HOW DOES E-LOAN SAFEGUARD MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

E-LOAN follows generally accepted industry standards to protect any personal information, including non-public personal information (such as Social Security Number, ABA Routing Number and Account Number) submitted to it, both during transmission and once such information are received. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while E-LOAN strives to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, E-LOAN cannot guarantee its absolute security. E-LOAN uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology supporting up to 128-bit encryption to prevent unauthorized parties from viewing any personal information transmitted to or from E-LOAN during your session. E-LOAN has also obtained a digital certificate from VeriSign for www.eloan.com and its subdomains.

**WILL THIS PRIVACY POLICY CHANGE?**

To accommodate changes on the E-LOAN Web site, changing technology, and legal developments, E-LOAN may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. E-LOAN will notify you in writing of significant changes to our information privacy practices, and will prominently post the current version of the Privacy Policy at the E-LOAN Web site. E-LOAN may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to E-LOAN’s information practices. If E-LOAN makes any material changes it will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Web site prior to the change becoming effective. E-LOAN encourages you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**E-LOAN DEPOSIT PRIVACY POLICY**

All deposit products offered through E-LOAN will be opened through Banco Popular North America (BPNA), a New York state chartered bank insured by the FDIC that is the direct parent company of E-LOAN (i.e. E-LOAN is a wholly-owned subsidiary of BPNA). Processing services are provided by BPNA. All deposits with BPNA are insured for the maximum amount allowed by law, and all balances on deposit with BPNA (whether directly or through E-LOAN) would be combined for purposes of determining FDIC coverage eligibility. Effective July 22, 2010, the new standard maximum deposit insurance amount (SMDIA) is made permanent to $250,000. Your deposits are insured up to $250,000 per depositor. You may qualify for more than $250,000 in coverage if you hold deposits in different account ownership categories. For more information about FDIC insurance coverage, visit [www.fdic.gov](https://www.fdic.gov/).

Because BPNA holds these accounts, we are providing you with a copy of their privacy policy, which applies to these deposit products. BPNA will use your information solely to provide services on these accounts.

Please click here to view the BPNA privacy policy.

Online Privacy Practices

E-LOAN has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, www.eloan.com.

If you have questions or complaints regarding E-LOAN’s Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us at 1-866-576-7283. If you are not satisfied with E-LOAN’s response you can contact TRUSTe at [feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Collection and Use of 3rd Party Personal Information

You may also provide personal information about other people, such as their name, relationship and their social security number. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided.

**CAN I ACCESS MY INFORMATION?**

You can access your account information at www.eloan.com anytime, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. Simply log in using the Username and Password you entered when you first opened your Savings or CD account. To further ensure your security; please note that three unsuccessful login attempts will lock your account. To unlock it, you will need to call an associate for assistance at 1-866-576-7283 Monday to Friday between the hours of 8:00 am and 5:00 pm Pacific Time. If you wish to cancel your account or request that E-LOAN no longer uses your information to provide you services contact E-LOAN by sending an email request using this form. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days

**WHAT ARE THE TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES USED BY E-LOAN?**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by E-LOAN and our advertising partners in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

  * Log Files

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

  * Local Storage Objects (HTML 5)

Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

  * Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

  * Frames

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to www.eloan.com.

  * Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Pinterest Pin It button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**HOW LONG WILL MY INFORMATION BE STORED?**

Federal and state agencies require that E-LOAN provide aggregated demographic and loan funding information about its loan applicants. E-LOAN maintains electronic and hardcopy loan application information for funded/declined/withdrawn loans for a period of at least 7 years in accordance with federal and state laws.

**WHO CAN I CONTACT FOR PRIVACY RELATED ISSUES?**

Please fill out our contact form to report any known or suspected privacy or security breaches or to submit privacy-related questions or complaints. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you may contact TRUSTe here. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with E-LOAN to resolve user concerns.

Contact us

To submit privacy-related questions or complaints:

Call 1 (866) 576-7283 — our menu will prompt you through your choice(s) or Visit us online: https://savings.eloan.com/optout

E-LOAN, Inc.

85 Broad St

10th Floor

New York, NY 10004

This is a hyperlink to a third-party website as described in our [Weblinking Practices](http://www.eloan.com/weblinking-practices). Note that the third party’s privacy policy and security practices may differ from E-LOAN standards. E-LOAN assumes no responsibility, nor does it control, endorse or guarantee any aspect of your use of the linked site.
